const dayThirtyQuestions = [
  {
    question:
      "How many people worldwide speak Arabic as either a first or second language?",
    options: [
      "Approximately 100 million",
      "Approximately 200 million",
      "Approximately 300 million",
      "Approximately 400 million",
    ],
    correctOption: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "Which language family does Arabic belong to?",
    options: ["Indo-European", " Afro-Asiatic", " Dravidian", " Sino-Tibetan"],
    correctOption: "1",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the official language of Egypt?",
    options: ["English", "French", "Arabic", "Persian"],
    correctOption: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which Arabic dialect is commonly understood across the Arab world?",
    options: [
      " Moroccan Arabic",
      " Egyptian Arabic",
      " Gulf Arabic",
      " Modern Standard Arabic",
    ],
    correctOption: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "How many letters are there in the Arabic alphabet?",
    options: ["22", "26", " 28", " 32"],
    correctOption: 0,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the direction of writing in the Arabic language?",
    options: [
      "Left-to-right",
      "Right-to-left",
      "Top-to-bottom",
      "Bottom-to-top",
    ],
    correctOption: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the term for the Arabic script used in decorative writing and calligraphy?",
    options: ["Naskh", "Thuluth", " Diwani", "Ruq’ah"],
    correctOption: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "How many grammatical cases are there in Arabic?",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    correctOption: 0,
  },
  {
    question: "Which Arabic term is used for the Islamic call to prayer?",
    options: ["Bismillah", "Insha’Allah", "Adhan", "Masha’Allah"],
    correctOption: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the term for the Arabic script used for writing the Quran?",
    options: ["Naskh", "Thuluth", "Kufic", "Diwani"],
    correctOption: 2,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following countries has Arabic as its official language?",
    options: ["Iran", "Turkey", "Saudi Arabia", "Pakistan"],
    correctOption: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Arabic term for 'hello'?",
    options: ["Salaam", "Marhaba", "Shukran", "As-salamu alaykum"],
    correctOption: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Arabic term for 'thank you'?",
    options: [" Ma’a salama", " Shukran", " Sabah al-khair", " Alhamdulillah"],
    correctOption: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the term for the Arabic art of storytelling?",
    options: ["Sufism", " Mawlid", " Hadith", "Hakawati"],
    correctOption: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Arabic term for 'peace be upon you'?",
    options: [" Insha’Allah", " Salam aleikum", " Mabrook", " Ramadan Kareem"],
    correctOption: 1,
  },
];

export default dayThirtyQuestions;
